Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- L'Afrique divisee en ses principales parties. = Africa divided into its principal parts. -- Paris: Robert de Vaugondy, the family of; Robert de Vaugondy, the family of; Robert de Vaugondy, the family of, 1748; NOR 0090; : Colored; 15.5 cm. x 19.5 cm.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0090, p. 106
  Norwich number: 0090
  RID: MOA 0182
- Afrique publicee sous les auspices de Monseigneur le Duc d'Orleans Primier Prince du Sang. = Africa published under the patronage of the Duke of Orleans. -- Paris: Anville, Jean Baptiste Bourguignon d', 1697-1782; Anville, Jean Baptiste Bourguignon d', 1697-1782; Anville, Jean Baptiste Bourguignon d', 1697-1782, 1749; NOR 0091; : Colored; 97 cm. x 97 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar features to Clouet's map (see NOR 0088). Large wall map of two double-folding sheets. Inset of Azores; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0091, p. 107
  Norwich number: 0091
  RID: MOA 0237
- L'Afrique divisee selon le tendue de tous ses etats assujetti aux observations astronomiques avec des nottes historiques et geographiques touchant les naturels de ce continent. = Africa divided into regions according to astronomical observations ... -- Lyon: Daudet; Bailleul, Gaspard, 1703-1781, 1752; NOR 0092; : Colored; 47 cm. x 61 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes the Mediterranean, Turkey, Arabia and the Middle East. "Borders consist of columns of historical and geographical descriptions." Dedication: Dediee et presentee a Messire Bertrand Rene Pallu; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0092, p. 109
  Norwich number: 0092
  RID: MOA 0087
- Africa arreglada a las mejores relacion[e]s ... = Africa agreeable to the best descriptions. -- Spain: Murillo Velarde, Pedro, 1696-1753; Murillo Velarde, Pedro, 1696-1753; Murillo Velarde, Pedro, 1696-1753, 1752; NOR 0093; : Uncolored; 16 cm. x 23 cm.
  Source: Geographia Historica Africa Arreglada a las Mejores Relaciones (1752)
  Descriptive Notes: "Shape of the south is unusual, with a bulge on the western coast."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0093, p. 110
  Norwich number: 0093
  RID: MOA 0032
- L'Afrique dressee sur les relations le plus recentes, et assujettie aux observations astronomique par ... Geog. du Roy, de Sa M. Polon, Due de Lorraine et de Bar et Associe de l'Academie Royale des Sciences et B. Lettres de Nancy, avec privilege. = Africa drawn according to recent reports. -- Paris: Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786; Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786; Robert de Vaugondy, Gilles, 1688-1766; Robert de Vaugondy, Didier, 1723-1786, 1756; NOR 0094; : Colored; 46 cm. x 59 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Cartouche illustrates a native woman reclining between two palms. Interior of southern Africa is fairly blank other than tribal names; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0094, p. 111
  Norwich number: 0094
  RID: MOA 0238
- Kaart van Afrika door den Heer d'Anville ... = Map of Africa after d'Anville. -- Amsterdam: Tirion, Isaak; Tirion, Isaak, 1763; NOR 0096; : Colored; 35 cm. x 35 cm.
  Source: Hedendaagsche Historie of Tegenwoordige Staat van Afrika ... (1763)
  Descriptive Notes: Based on d'Anville's map (see NOR 0091). Inset of Vlaamsche Eilanden; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0096, p. 113
  Norwich number: 0096
  RID: MOA 0164
- L'Afrique Dresee pour l'etude de la Geographie. -- Paris: Brion de la Tour, Louis; Desnos, L.C.; Brion de la Tour, Louis; Desnos, L.C., 1766; NOR 0097; : Colored; 23 cm. x 26 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: French text within the decorative borders provide detailed description of Africa; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0097, p. 114
  Norwich number: 0097
  RID: MOA 0111
- Africa Drawn from the latest and best Authorities. -- London: Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784, 1770; NOR 0098; : Colored; 34 cm. x 37 cm.
  Source: New Geographical Grammer (1770)
  Descriptive Notes: Gold mines are indicated south of Zimbabwe. Title across top, Engraved for Guthrie's new Geographical Grammar; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0098, p. 115
  Norwich number: 0098
  RID: MOA 0177
- L'Africa divisa ne'suoi Principali Stati Di Nuova Projezione. = Africa divided into its principal states. -- Venice: Zatta, Antonio, fl. 1757-1797; Zatta, Antonio, fl. 1757-1797; Zatta, Antonio, fl. 1757-1797, 1776; NOR 0099; : Outline color; 30 cm. x 39 cm.
  Source: Atlante Novissiomo (1775-1785)
  Descriptive Notes: Based on Janvier's map (see NOR 0104). "Fairly accurate geographically and unknown parts of the country are marked as such instead of being dotted with fictitious places"; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0099, p. 116
  Norwich number: 0099
  RID: MOA 0165
- L'Afrique divesee en ses principaux etats. = Africa divided into its principal states. -- Paris: Lattre, Jean; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794, 1778; NOR 0100; : Colored; 70 cm. x 98 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map correctly describes known geography of the east and west coast. The cartouche illustrates a person in oriental turban and dress, reclining on a lion. Two insets: Isle Bourbon and Isle de France; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0100, p. 117
  Norwich number: 0100
  RID: MOA 0101
- Africa, agreeable to the most approved maps and charts. -- London: Conder, Thomas, 1746 or 7-1831; Conder, Thomas, 1746 or 7-1831, 1779; NOR 0102; : Outline color; 33 cm. x 37 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Above the square shaped cartouche, sits a native surrounded by a lion, a bird and a camel. Title across the top: Engraved for Moore's New and Compleat Collection of Voyages and Travels; Prime meridian through London and Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0102, p. 119
  Norwich number: 0102
  RID: MOA 0167
- Afrique. -- Unknown Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794, 1782; NOR 0103; : Colored; 21 cm. x 32 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "Arrows in the oceans probably indicate the monsoons because those depicted at the top right are named by months"; Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0103, p. 120
  Norwich number: 0103
  RID: MOA 0102
- L'Afrique divisee en ses principaux Etats. = Africa divided into its principal parts. -- Paris: Janvier, Jean; Janvier, Jean; Janvier, Jean, 1782; NOR 0104; : Outline color; 30 cm. x 43.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche depicts a forest-like setting with a leopard, a bird and a crocodile. Top right: 28.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0104, p. 121
  Norwich number: 0104
  RID: MOA 0159
- Africa with all its States, Kingdoms, Republics, Regions, Islands, etc, Improved and Inlarged from d'Anville's Map; to which have been Added A Particular Chart of the Gold Coast, wherein are Distinguished all the European Forts and Factories. -- London: Sayer, Robert, 1725-1794; Boulton, S., 1787; NOR 0105; : Outline color; 51 cm. x 123 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This two-sheet map was first issued by Boulton under J.B.B. d'Anville's name in 1772 and reissued in 1787, (see map 0091). Insets include, Azores; A Particular Chart of the Gold Coast; A summary description relative to the trade and natural produce, manner and customs of the African continent and islands; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0105, p. 122
  Norwich number: 0105
  RID: MOA 0103
- L'Africa divisa nelle sue principali parti. = Africa divided into its principal parts. -- Siena: Carli, Pazzini, fl. late 18th c.; Carli, Pazzini, fl. late 18th c., 1788; NOR 0106; : Outline color; 22.5 cm. x 31 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche includes a floral wreath with a face; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0106, p. 124
  Norwich number: 0106
  RID: MOA 0117
- Africa with all its States, Regions, Islands ca. from the most Approved Authorities. -- London: Sayer, Robert, 1725-1794; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784, 1789; NOR 0107; : Colored; 44 cm. x 53 cm.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0107, p. 125
  Norwich number: 0107
  RID: MOA 0199
- Charte de L'Afrique. = Map of Africa. -- Augsberg: Walch, Jean (fl. Late 18th c.); Walch, Jean (fl. Late 18th c.); Walch, Jean (fl. Late 18th c.), 1790; NOR 0108; : Colored; 46 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Depicts an accurate outline of the continent. The cartouche includes a native surrounded by foliage. Nearby are a monkey, a crocodile and two elephant's tusks.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0108, p. 126
  Norwich number: 0108
  RID: MOA 0201
- L'Afrique Divisee en ses Empires, Royaumes et Etats Dresses Sur Les Dernieres Observations. = Africa divided into empires, kingdoms and states ... -- Amsterdam: Elwe, Jan Barend; Elwe, Jan Barend, 1792; NOR 0109; : Colored; 45 cm. x 59 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Identical to Jaillot's map (see NOR 0046), except for the scale; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0109, p. 127
  Norwich number: 0109
  RID: MOA 0248
- Africa nach Robert Vaugondy, Rennell's und Solzmann's Skizze des nordlichen Theils von Africa ... = Africa according to ... -- Nurnberg: Schneider, Adam Gottlieb, 1745-1815; Weigel, Johann Christoph, d. 1746; Schneider, Adam Gottlieb, 1745-1815; Weigel, Johann Christoph, d. 1746, 1794; NOR 0111; : Colored; 52 cm. x 58.5 cm.
  Source: Atlas der Georgraphie von der bekannten ganzen welt (1794-1805)
  Descriptive Notes: Color index identifies countries holding power in Africa, however historically incorrect. Inset: Die Azorischen Inseln; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0111, p. 129
  Norwich number: 0111
  RID: MOA 0316
- Charte von Africa nach astronomischen Beobachtungen, auch alten und neuen Nachrichten, ingleichen den Charten von Sayer, Rennel, Arrowsmit ... = Map of Africa according to astronomical observations and information found on the maps of Sayer, Rennel and Arrowsmith. -- Nurnberg: Homann Heirs; Gussefeld, F. L. (Franz Ludwig), 1744-1807, 1797; NOR 0112; : Colored; 46 cm. x 15.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Note states "accurate geographical knowledge of the interior will only be available after further exploration"; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0112, p. 130
  Norwich number: 0112
  RID: MOA 0196
- Afrique avec ses principales Divisions et leurs Capitales. = Africa with its principal regions and their capitals. -- Unknown: Anonymous; Anonymous, No date; NOR 0113; : Colored; 22.5 cm. x 28 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris. Top right: 4.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0113, p. 131
  Norwich number: 0113
  RID: MOA 0244
- Mappe Monde, Sur Un Plan Horisontal. Situe a 45d de latitude Nord. Hemiphere Oriental. = World map, 45 degree plane, eastern hemisphere. -- Unknown Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794, No date; NOR 0114; : Uncolored; 23 cm. x 23 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: World map of the eastern hemisphere includes the Arctic Circle. Two insets: Effet de la pesanteur and Sphere oblique; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0114, p. 132
  Norwich number: 0114
  RID: MOA 0033
  Africa -- World map, eastern hemiphere -- 18th c.
- An Accurate Map of Africa Drawn from the best Authorities. -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767.; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767.; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767., NOR 0115; : Uncolored; 18 cm. x 22 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes a portion of the bulge of Brazil; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0115, p. 133
  Norwich number: 0115
  RID: MOA 0034
- Afrique. -- Paris: Chamouin, Jean-Baptiste-Marie, b.1768; Chamouin, Jean-Baptiste-Marie, b.1768; Chamouin, Jean-Baptiste-Marie, b.1768; Giraldon, No date; NOR 0116; : Outline color; 22 cm. x 30 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche illustrates a "sphinx-like animal sitting on a rectangular masonry block with the title 'Afrique' on it"; Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0116, p. 134
  Norwich number: 0116
  RID: MOA 0118
- Africa including the Mediterranean. -- London: Wilkinson, Robert, d. ca. 1825.; Wilkinson, Robert, d. ca. 1825.; Wilkinson, Robert, d. ca. 1825.; Baker, E., 1800; NOR 0117; : Colored; 28 cm. x 22 cm.
  Source: General Atlas of the World
  Descriptive Notes: Reduced from a four-sheet map. Fairly accurate except for the narrow, tappered southern tip; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0117, p. 135
  Norwich number: 0117
  RID: MOA 0173
- Africa, and its Several Regions and Islands according to the most recent Descriptions. -- London: Robert Laurie and James Whittle; Laurie, Robert, 1755-1836; Whittle, James, 1800; NOR 0118; : Colored; 45.5 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Even though the map depicts extensive knowledge of the interior, "the great rivers are inaccurately placed and the Nile erroneously appears to originate in two adjacent lakes in Central Africa"; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0118, p. 136
  Norwich number: 0118
  RID: MOA 0206
  Africa -- Africa -- 19th c.
- Atlas Des Ganzen Erdkreises in der Central Projection. = Map of part of the world ... -- Unknown: Reichard, C. G. (Christian Gottlieb), 1758-1837; Reichard, C. G. (Christian Gottlieb), 1758-1837, 1803; NOR 0120; : Outline color; 43 cm. x 42 cm.
  Source: Atlas Ganzen Erdkreises (1803)
  Descriptive Notes: Extends to include the Mediterranean, the Middle East, Arabia and part of Asia and India.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0120, p. 139
  Norwich number: 0120
  RID: MOA 0204
- Africa. -- London: Smith, Charles, map publisher; Smith, Charles, map publisher, No date; NOR 0121; : Colored; 35 cm. x 26 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes the Mediterranean and part of Arabia. "The west coast of Africa illustrates the Guinea, Ivory and Grain Coasts". Top right: 42; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0121, p. 140
  Norwich number: 0121
  RID: MOA 0171
- Africa. -- Philadelphia: Dobson, Thomas, 1751-1823; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Pinkerton, John, 1758-1826; Herbert, J., No date; NOR 0122; : Colored; 69 cm. x 50 cm.
  Source: Modern Atlas (1815)
  Descriptive Notes: Much of the geography proves to be inaccurate due to the fact it was based on antiquarian maps. "Large tracts of the interior of Africa are marked unknown". Across the top: Pinkerton's Modern Atlas.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0122, p. 141
  Norwich number: 0122
  RID: MOA 0317
- North Africa and South Africa. -- Edinburgh: John Thomson Co.; John Thomson Co. Exploration, 1814; NOR 0123; : Colored; 27 cm. x 51 cm.
  Source: New General Atlas (1814)
  Descriptive Notes: Two separate maps of north and south Africa indicates routes of several explorers. Bottom: Drawn and engraved for Thomson's New General Atlas. Bottom right: No. 49.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0123, p. 142
  Norwich number: 0123
  RID: MOA 0276
- Carte de L'Afrique Divisee en ses principaux Etats pour servir a l'instruction de la Jeunesse. = Map of Africa divided into states ... -- Paris: Basset; Herisson, Eustache, 1759-, 1821; NOR 0125; : Colored; 50 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Illustrates "routes of Cook's voyages of 1771, 1775 and 1780 around the Cape of Good Hope to Australia". Borders decribe African states; Prime meridian through Paris and Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0125, p. 144
  Norwich number: 0125
  RID: MOA 0319
- Africa. -- 1821: Woodbridge, William C. (William Channing), 1794-1845; Woodbridge, William C. (William Channing), 1794-1845, Hartford, Connecticut; NOR 0126; : Colored; 20 cm. x 26 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The central part of Africa is referred to as 'Ethiopia an unexplored region'; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0126, p. 145
  Norwich number: 0126
  RID: MOA 0191
- Carte Physique et Politique de L'Afrique. = Physical and political map of Africa. -- Paris: Brue, Adrien Hubert, 1786-1832; Brue, Adrien Hubert, 1786-1832, 1822; NOR 0127; : Outline color; 57 cm. x 85 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The shape appears to be accurate, including the geographical detail, with the exception of the center blank space. "The areas belonging to different native tribes are shown more accurately than in many other maps at this time"; Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0127, p. 146
  Norwich number: 0127
  RID: MOA 0114
- Africa. -- London: Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839, 1825; NOR 0128; : Outline color; 22.5 cm. x 30 cm.
  Source: Outlines of the World (1825)
  Descriptive Notes: Bottom right: 33; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0128, p. 147
  Norwich number: 0128
  RID: MOA 0084
- Africa. -- London: Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839; Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839, 1828; NOR 0129; : Outline color; 24 cm. x 27 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The southeast coast is marked 'Sterile Coast.' The Portuguese settlements on the eastern coast are noted. Top right: 4; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0129, p. 148
  Norwich number: 0129
  RID: MOA 0085
- Africa According to the best Authorities. -- Philadelphia: Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839; Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839, No date; NOR 0130; : Outline color; 33.5 cm. x 33.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map was issued in Carey's General Atlas and also in Gunthrie's Geography Improved. Geographically the map is not accurate, states fictitious tribal names and inaccurate naming of bays and rivers. Title across top: Engraved for Carey's American edition of Gunthrie's Geography Improved; Prime meridian through Philadelphia.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0130, p. 149
  Norwich number: 0130
  RID: MOA 0116
- Carte Generale de L'Afrique. = General map of Africa. -- Paris: Mentelle, E. (Edme), 1730-1815; Mentelle, E. (Edme), 1730-1815, 1829; NOR 0131; : Outline color; 31 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris. Top left: No. 150.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0131, p. 150
  Norwich number: 0131
  RID: MOA 0271
- Eastern Hemisphere. -- London: Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839; Arrowsmith, Samuel, d. 1839, 1828; NOR 0132; : Outline color; 22.5 cm. x 22.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Eastern hemisphere of the world map, on a typical Mercator projection. Top left: 1.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0132, p. 151
  Norwich number: 0132
  RID: MOA 0086
  Africa -- Eastern Hemisphere -- 19th c.
- Africa. -- London: Teesdale, Henry; Teesdale, Henry; Teesdale, Henry, 1831; NOR 0133; : Colored; 41 cm. x 33 cm.
  Source: General Atlas (1831)
  Descriptive Notes: Illustrates an accurate map of the continent of Africa. Top right: 33; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0133, p. 152
  Norwich number: 0133
  RID: MOA 0189
- Carta dell' Africa che serve d'illustrazione al nuovo Dizionario Geographico Universale ... = Map of Africa forming part of a new gazeteer ... -- Venice: Antonelli, Giuseppe, 1793-1861; Antonelli, Giuseppe, 1793-1861, 1832; NOR 0134; : Uncolored; 34 cm. x 46 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map includes the Mediterranean, Arabia and the bulge of Brazil; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0134, p. 153
  Norwich number: 0134
  RID: MOA 0156
- Africa. -- Philadelphia: Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858; Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858, 1834; NOR 0135; : Colored; 29 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Colored legend illustrates the various European powers. Title across top: Tanner's Universal Atlas. Insets of Liberia and Monrovia. Bottom right: 61; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0135, p. 154
  Norwich number: 0135
  RID: MOA 0179
- Africa. -- London: Wyld, James, 1812-1887; Delarochette, L.; Delarochette, L., 1835; NOR 0136; : Outline color; 51 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First published in 1803, later re-issued in 1835, 1838 and 1840. Inset: Azores or Western Islands; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0136, p. 155
  Norwich number: 0136
  RID: MOA 0294
- Africa. -- London: Virtue, George, 1793?-1868; Virtue, George, 1793?-1868; Virtue, George, 1793?-1868, 1836-1839; NOR 0137; : Outline color; 24 cm. x 19 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Accurate outline of the continent; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0137, p. 156
  Norwich number: 0137
  RID: MOA 0190
- Africa. -- London: Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge (Great Britain); Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge; Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge, 1839; NOR 0138; : Colored; 31 cm. x 39 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This map was highly influential due to the accuracy of information; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0138, p. 157
  Norwich number: 0138
  RID: MOA 0166
- Africa. -- London: Cruchley, G. F.; Cruchley, G. F.; Cruchley, G. F., 1841; NOR 0139; : Colored; 34.5 cm. x 44.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Title across top: Cruchley's Improved Atlas for Schools and Families. Top right: 27; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0139, p. 158
  Norwich number: 0139
  RID: MOA 0181
- Afrique. -- Paris: Combette, A.; Levasseur, Victor; Levasseur, Victor; Bonheur, Raimond, 1840 ca.; NOR 0140; : Outline color; 29 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "Framework consists of landscape, fruit, foliage and animals, with descriptive text and statistical information on towns and islands." Three insets include Alexandria, Cairo and Algiers. Top left: Atlas Universel Illustre. Top right: Ancien continent.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0140, p. 159
  Norwich number: 0140
  RID: MOA 0184
- Carte d'Afrique. = Map of Africa. -- Paris Lapie, Alexandre Emile; Lapie, M. (Pierre), 1779-1850; Lapie, Alexandre Emile; Lapie, M. (Pierre), 1779-1850, 1851; NOR 0141; : Colored; 39 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Surrounding islands are similar to Brue's 1822 map (see NOR 0127); Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0141, p. 160
  Norwich number: 0141
  RID: MOA 0269